<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_infantry_ranged">
  <Armour>
    <Hack>2</Hack>
    <Pierce>2</Pierce>
  </Armour>
  <Attack>
    <Ranged>
      <Hack>0</Hack>
      <Pierce>16.0</Pierce>
      <Crush>0</Crush>
      <MaxRange>24.0</MaxRange>
      <MinRange>0.0</MinRange>
      <ProjectileSpeed>62.5</ProjectileSpeed>
      <PrepareTime>750</PrepareTime>
      <RepeatTime>1250</RepeatTime>
      <Spread>4.0</Spread>
    </Ranged>
  </Attack>
  <Cost>
    <Resources>
      <wood>55</wood>
    </Resources>
  </Cost>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>gaia</Civ>
	<Lang>greek</Lang>
	<Rank>Basic</Rank>
	<GenericName>Light Peltast</GenericName>
    <SpecificName>Euzonòs</SpecificName>
    <SelectionGroupName>units/hele_infantry_javelinist_b</SelectionGroupName>
    <VisibleClasses datatype="tokens">Javelin Thureos</VisibleClasses>
    <History>The thureophoroi (singular: thureophoros) was a type of infantry soldier, common in the 3rd to 1st century BCE, who carried a large oval shield called a thureos which had a type of metal strip boss and a central spine. They were armed with a long thrusting spear, javelins and a sword. They also usually wore an iron or bronze Macedonian helmet. The thureos was probably originally an adapted form of a Celtic shield. Thracian and Illyrian infantry probably adopted the shield before the Greeks. However it has been suggested that the thureos was brought to Greece after Pyrrhus of Epirus' campaigns in Italy, as his Oscan allies and Roman enemies used the scutum. Thureophoroi were a 3rd century development on the Peltast and wore no body armor, but did wear sturdy leather boots for quick movement. Thureophoroi could skirmish, as well as fight in a phalanx when necessary. They were often stationed on the flanks of the traditional pike phalanx as a flexible link between the heavier pikemen and the cavalry wings.</History>
    <Icon>units/ptol_infantry_javelinist.png</Icon>
  </Identity>
  <Loot>
    <wood>5</wood>
  </Loot>
  <Promotion>
    <Entity>units/hele_infantry_javelinist_a</Entity>
  </Promotion>
  <UnitMotion>
    <WalkSpeed op="mul">1.3</WalkSpeed>
    <Run>
      <Speed op="mul">1.3</Speed>
    </Run>
  </UnitMotion>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/ptolemies/infantry_javelinist_b.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
